So now with links implemented, let's work on these orders again
imdi balantlar uyguladmzda, bu emirler zerinde tekrar alalm.
and on the orders, I actually want to adjust the styling for a single order, the width should only be
Ve bu emirlerde aslnda tek bir sipari iin ekillendirmeyi ayarlamak istiyorum, yalnzca
let's say 80%,
80 yzde 80 diyelim.
to not span dthe full width.
Tam genilii harcamak deil.
Still I went to fetch these orders from my server
Hala bu siparileri sunucudan almaya geldim.
and for that I'll first of all create two orders.
Ve bunun iin ncelikle iki emir yaratr.
So create two burgers, maybe this burger here let me continue continue and order it and let me trade
Yani iki tane Burger yaratn, belki bu burger bana devam etmeme izin verin ve sipari verin ve bir tane daha ticaret yapmama
one more
izin verin.
just meat and bacon,
Sadece et ve domuz pastrmas.
super healthy burger here, let's click continue,
Sper salkl burger burada devam etmeye devam edelim.
continue and order it.
Devam edin ve sipari edin.
And now if you check the firebase database, we see two orders here,
Ve imdi, gvenlik duvar veritabanna bakarsanz, burada iki sipari grrz.
we also see that the price is off here but we'll fix this by outputting it correctly in the order.
Ayrca, fiyatn burada olduunu gryoruz, ancak bunu srayla doru bir ekilde kartarak dzeltiyoruz.
Still the outputting part is the one we're not doing right now,
Yine de k ksm u anda yapmadmz paradr.
In the orders container I obviously want to fetch all my orders. Now to do that
Sipariler konteynrnda akas bunu yapmak iin btn emirlerimi almak istiyorum.
I will implement componentDidMount.
Bileen bor yklemesini uygulayacam.
I can use componentDidMount here because I only want to fetch orders when this is loaded,
Bileen miktarn burada kullanabilirim, nk yalnzca yklendiinde emirleri almak istiyorum.
there is no way we will go there with out remounting it
Oraya gidip onu yeniden balamamzn bir yolu yok.
So componentDidUpdate is not what I'm looking for,
Yani bu gncelleme deil aradm ey aradm ey deil.
so componentDidMount is what I need.
Dolaysyla bu miktar, ihtiyacm olan miktardr.
I also need axios
Ayrca X ylna ihtiyacm var.
So I'm going to import axios here from my own instance.
Bu yzden kendi eriimimden buraya eriim alacam.
So import axios from
O zaman aksiyomlar ithal edin.
and now let's go up till we have axios-orders.js here and then here I want to reach out to
gelene kadar yukar kalm ve burada aslnda emir almak iin uzlamak istiyoruz.
axios.get get orders.json
imdi X yl emir alp Chaiya'ya
referring to that orders node on my backend
Jason arka ucumdaki l sipari dmne atfta bulundu.
and we set this as the baseURL on our own axios instance so I don't have to add this.
Ve dedik ki, S-D, L'nizi kendi X-ists rneimize dayandryor, bu yzden buna gerek yok.
And then, once the data is there, of course we waant to do something with the response, I want to set some
Ve sonra veriler bir kez tabii ki yantla bir eyler yapmak istiyor, aslnda siparilerimi
state which actually contains my orders and then outputs them.
ieren ve bunlar kartan baz devleti kurmak istiyorum.
So i'll add some stage to this component here, now in the state,
Dolaysyla bir ksm 2. etapta u an devletin iinde olan bileen.
I want to have my orders which is an array, an empty array initially and I'll probably also have a loading
Balangta bir dizi ve bo bir dizi olan emirlerimi vermek istiyorum ve muhtemelen balangta
state which initially is true because I'll start loading,
doru olan kayan bir duruma geleceim, nk yklemeye balayacam.
and then here in the then block, I'll definitely call set state and set loading to false. I'll also do this
Ve sonra buraya ve sonra engellemek set devlet arayacam ve iki yanl boa ykleme
in the catch block here where I catch any potential errors.
burada olas herhangi bir hatay yakalamak catch blou burada dedi.
So there I'll definitely also copy that line and set loading to false. But of course also I want to
Dolaysyla kesinlikle kopyann son teslim tarihi ve iki kat ykleme dedi, ancak elbette
store my orders.
siparilerimi de saklamak istiyorum.
Now the thing is when I reach out to the orders node, I'm not getting an array but I'll get back a
imdi sra ulatmzda bir diziyi almadmz bir ey ama bir javascript nesnesinin tm basite
javascript object, I'll simply print it to the console so that we can analyze it res.data will hold the
konsola yazdrlm bir ekilde geri alacam, bylece ey analiz edebiliyoruz, bylece dinlenme verileri elde ettiimiz
data we get from firebase
verileri alacak Firebase.
so let's have a look at that data then.
O halde bu verilere bir gz atalm.
We head over to our application, open the console and go to orders, this is the object we'll get back
Ardndan, konsolumuzun ak olduu uygulamamza geip, anahtarlarn sadece Deis benzersiz kimlik belgeleri
from firebase and as you see, it's a javascript object where the keys are simply these unique IDs firebase generated
reten ve deerimiz bireysel sipari verisini densiz hale getiren bir javascript
for us and the value then is the individual order data.
nesnesi grdnden, nesne alev alanndan geri dnecektir.
So we're not getting back an array but we get back an object where we have the IDs as properties.
Bylece sraya geri dnmyoruz, ancak zellik olarak kimlikleri bulunduumuz bir nesneye geri dnyoruz.
Now what I want to do is, I of course want to turn my orders object into an array and I can simply do
imdi yapmak istediim, elbette emirler nesnemi bir diziye evirmek istiyorum ve bunu yalnzca bir for
that by using a for/in loop.
dngs kullanarak yapabilirim.
So for let key in res.data and remember rest data is an object we just printed to the console and
yleyse dinlenme verilerindeki kurun anahtar ve dinlenme verilerini hatrlamak yalnzca yeni bir konsolda yazdrdmz bir nesne
then here, I want to create a little helper method, fetchedOrders or whatever you want
ve daha sonra burada kk bir yardmc yntem getirilmi sipariler veya ne isterseniz almak istiyoruz.
it's an empty array initially and I will simply call fetchedOrders.push for each iteration or for each
Balangta bo bir dizimdir ve yalnzca bulduum her e iin her yineleme iin
element I find and I want to push res.data for a given key, accessing the value which of course is
getirilen emirleri aracam ve tabii ki sipari deerine erien belirli bir anahtar iin dinlenenin verilerini
the order.
itmek istiyorum.
Now with that, we have the fetchedOrders array, to not lose the IDs though which are my keys here.
imdi bununla birlikte kimliklerimizi kaybetmemek iin emirler getirdik, ancak anahtarlarm burada.
I'll do one thing,
Bir ey yapacam.
I'll not push this object, I'll instead push a new object onto this fetchedOrders array where I
siparilerinde, spread operatryle birlikte Firebase'ten getirdiim Order nesnesinin zelliklerini dataca ve yapkan bir yeni
will distribute the properties off the Order object I've fetched from firebase with the spread operator
zellik kimlii ekleyecei bir oranda yeni bir nesne itin. anahtar, temel
and add one new property ID which is the key because remember the key is in this object we've fetched
szcmzden, gvenlik duvar tarafndan oluturulan kimlikleri alp getirdiimiz bu nesnede unutmayn.
from firebase where the ID's created by firebase.
Bu nesneyi itmem, aksine bugnn toplu
So now I have my fetchedOrders array full of order objects which also are aware of their IDs.
imdi, getirilen emirlerimin kimliklerinin farknda olduu sipari nesneleri dolu bir dizi var.
Now I can set orders here to fetchedOrders,
imdi buraya getirilen emirler iin emir verebilirim.
I of course also want to handle any potential errors so I'll import my own higher order component,
Tabii ki olas herhangi bir hatay da ele almak istiyorum, bu yzden kendi yksek sipari bileenim
withErrorHandler from
ile hata ileyicisini ie aktaracam.
and now we have to move up to that HOC folder, withErrorHandler/withErrorHandler and wrap our
Ve imdi, hata ileyicisine sahip bir hata ileyicisi olan Agios bakn klasrne geip, emir
orders component with it, withErrorHandler just like that,
bileenimizi onun gibi bir hata ileyicisi ile sarmamz gerekiyor.
wrapped like this.
Byle sarn.
Of course, let's also pass axios here, otherwise this won't work
Elbette burada gemiteki tm eylemler, ie yaramayacak kadar akll olsun.
and now let's try it out by removing this json ending here,
Ve imdi, Jason'n burada bitmesini kaldrarak deneyelim.
let's go back and we get the network error here.
Geri gidelim ve burada a hatas alyoruz.
So we got this error so this works,
Bu yzden bu hata var, bu ie yaryor.
the error handler. Of course you can fine tune it in the local catch method here to show an error message
Hata ileyicisi elbette ekranda bir hata mesaj grntlemek iin yerel yakalama ynteminde ince ayar yapabilir
on the screen or whatever you want.
veya ne istersen isteyebilirsiniz.
I'll re-add the .json
DOT'de alre.
here for the moment
Jason ileri doru bir dakika.
and with that, we are fetching our orders. Now fetching orders is of course not the same as outputting
Ve bununla beraber emirleri getirdiimiz iin emirlerimizi alyoruz elbette emir karma kadar
orders,
deil.
so let's do this in the next lecture.
O halde bunu bir sonraki derste yapalm.